                CONSENT FOR EXTRACTION OF TEETH

Extraction of teeth is an irreversible process and, whether routine or difficult, is a surgical 
procedure. As in any surgery, there are some risks. They include, but are not limited to:

     1. Swelling and/or bruising and discomfort in the surgery area.
     2. Stretching of the corners of the mouth resulting in cracking and bruising.
     3. Possible infection requiring further treatment.
     4. Dry socket--jaw pain beginning a few days after surgery, usually requiring 
       additional care. It is more common from lower extractions, especially wisdom 
       teeth.
     5. Possible damage to adjacent teeth, especially those with large fillings or 
       caps.
     6. Numbness or altered sensation in the teeth, lip, tongue and chin, due to the 
       closeness of tooth roots (especially wisdom teeth) to the nerves which can be 
       bruised or injured. Sensation most often returns to normal, but in rare cases, 
       the loss may be permanent.
     7. Trismus--limited jaw opening due to inflammation or swelling, most common 
       after wisdom tooth removal. Sometimes it is the result of jaw joint discomfort 
       (TMJ), especially when TMJ disease and symptoms already exist.
     8. Bleeding--significant bleeding is not common, but persistent oozing can be 
       expected for several hours.
     9. Sharp ridges or bone splinters may form later at the edge of the socket. 
       These may require another surgery to smooth or remove them.
     10. Incomplete removal of tooth fragments--to avoid injury to vital structures such 
       as nerves or sinuses, sometimes small root tips may be left in place. Sinus 
       involvement: the roots of upper back teeth are often close to the sinus and 
       sometimes a piece of root can be displaced into the sinus, or an opening 
       may occur into the mouth which may require additional care.
     11. Jaw fracture--while quite rare, it is possible in difficult or deeply impacted 
       teeth.

Most procedures are routine and serious complications are not expected. Those which do 
occur are most often minor and can be treated.

Teeth to be extracted: 

Alternatives to the above treatment: 

FOR PATIENTS NEEDING PARTIALS OR DENTURES. The PCHC Dental Department does 
not make dentures or partials. In some cases, the private practice dentist you have chosen to 
make your appliances may recommend you need further surgery to reshape the bone, 
alveoloplasty.

I have read and understand the above, and had my questions answered. I recognize there can 
be no warranty as to the outcome of treatment, and I give my consent to surgery.


Patient's (Legal Guardian's) Signature Date



Doctor's Signature                     Date



Witness Signature                      Date

winworclkkaren\con-ext 
8/98

