         CONSENT FOR TREATMENT BY AN EXTERN DENTIST


PCHC participates in Dental School programs for the University of Colorado Dental 
School and the University ofNorth Carolina Dental School. Through this program you 
will be treated by an extern dentist

Your extern dentist has completed training at the School of Dentistry. Many externs 
prior to their graduation spend time providing patient treatment under the supervision of 
experienced dentists, in dental clinics, which are not on the University campus.

Dr.            will supervise your treatment by the extern dentist. This
experienced, licensed dentist is a member of the faculty at the University of Colorado 
School of Dentistry and the University ofNorth Carolina Dental School.

Your extern is not licensed to practice dentistry, except as an extern who is supervised by 
the faculty member.

Please feel free to ask the supervising dentist or the extern questions at any time. This 
form is consent for treatment by the extern. If you wish to receive treatment from an 
extern, please read this form carefully. Then sign and date the consent for treatment, 
below.
"I have read and understand this consent form. I give my consent to receive treatment 
from an extern dentist"



Extern's Name       Patient/Parent/Guardian Date


Extern's Name       Patient/Parent/Guardian Date


Extern's Name       Patient/Parent/Guardian Date


Extent's Name       Patient/Parent/Guardian Date

